Welcome to Prompt Compression and Query
Optimization.
Built in partnership with MongoDB
and taught by Richmond Alake.
Richmond is a developer advocate at MongoDB
and has worked
as a machine learning architect and taught
AI and ML for many years.
Thanks, Andrew.
This course shows you how to combine
features of a mature, established database
with vector search to reduce the cost
of serving a large RAG application.
Say you're building
a conversational RAG application
that helps users select a rental property.
A user might enter a text query
for one level ranch on a quiet street.
You can use semantic search to find a
close match to the user description.
Using an embedding of the user requests
and searching a vector database for homes
with descriptions that match.
But the user may also have hard
requirements like
three bedrooms, two bathrooms,
and maybe no swimming pool.
These are better handled
with a more traditional retrieval
by selecting data
based on fields in the database
and explicitly store the number of bedrooms,
bathrooms, and so on.
In this course,
you learn to use the best of both worlds,
a traditional database
with an added vector index.
In RAG applications to retrieve results
that provide an LLM for final processing.
If the retrieve context is very long,
this results in a very long prompt
and can thus be costly where retrieval
to return, say 10,000 tokens.
If you were to run a rental comparison
website to search, say, a million
queries per day, and if LLM input tokens cost
$10 per million tokens,
you could be spending over
$36 million a year.
So, to help you reduce costs,
this course, will also cover ways
to keep the retrieved results
as small and relevant as possible.
Thanks, Andrew.
Let me describe some of the techniques
you will learn.
Let's consider your rental app
filtering on the number of bedrooms
or bathrooms can be done with a pre-filter
or post-filter.
Efficient pre-filter is done
in the database index creation stage.
You build a new index of entries
that match common queries.
So for example,
if you know you frequently get queries
for bedroom units, you can build an index
that includes the bedroom field.
So that's pre-filtering.
In contrast, post filtering is done
often a vector search query is performed
where you then apply a filter
to this result to select the sub set matching
the required condition.
Large scale applications may use
both of these techniques simultaneously.
Another technique to minimize
the size of the output is something called
projection, which selects a subset
of the fields returned from a query.
For example,
out of 15 fields of a potential rental,
you may want to return only three of them.
Name, number of bedrooms, and price.
Now, you could implement all of this
operation directly in your application,
but the database can optimize
all this operation
for performance and enforce
role-based access control.
So they are best accomplished there.
And another powerful technique
is reranking the results of a search.
For example, after using the text
embeddings of the renter description
to perform a semantic search,
you can rerank the results based on
other data fields such as average star
rating or number of ratings,
to move the more desired results
higher up the list of results.
In order to then generate
better context for the LLM.
One final technique is prompt compression.
If the retrieve information
is very lengthy,
seeking all this context
into an LLM prompt
results in a very long, prompt length,
which is expensive to process.
To reduce this costs,
you can use a small, low cost LLM fine
tuned to compress prompts
before sending them to the final LLM.
There are many opportunities
to improve relevance and save costs.
Thank you Andrew.
You will learn all these techniques
in the next few lesson.
You will start this course
by implementing a vanilla
vector search
and end by implementing prompts
compression.
Many people have worked
to create this course from MongoDB.
I'd like to thank Apoorva Joshi,
Pavel Duchovny, Prakul Agarwal,
Jesse Hall, Rita Rodrigues,
Henry Weller and Shubham Ranjan,
and also Esmaeil Gargari from DeepLearning.AI
had also contributed to this course.
I hope you enjoy this course.
Please
go to the next video and let's dive in.